Guide to the Joan Lipton papers, 1963-2001 and undated RL.11560
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Joan Lipton papers
1963-2001 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lipton, Joan
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11560
0.2 Linear Feet
Advertising executive who worked for a number of New York agencies, including Benton & Bowles and McCann Erickson. Collection includes clippings, proof pages, storyboards, writings, speeches and other printed materials that primarily document Lipton's career at McCann Erickson during the 1970s and 1980s. Advertisements relate to a variety of personal consumer products including lotions and other cosmetics, baby care, contraception and family planning. Companies represented include Gillette, Johnson & Johnson, Mennen (now part of Colgate-Palmolive), Ortho, Pepperell, and Tampax. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive who worked for a number of New York agencies, including Benton & Bowles and McCann Erickson. Born 1927; BA Barnard College 1948; Young & Rubicam: Television and radio writer, 1948-1952; Robert Orr & Associates: Supervisor of Television Advertising and Programming 1952-1957; Benton & Bowles: Copy Group Head 1957-1964, Associate Director and Copy Chief 1964-1967; McCann Erickson: Vice President and Creative Director 1968-1985; Martin & Lipton: President 1985-1990. Died 2015. Awards: Advertising Woman of the Year 1974, 1984; Matrix Award 1979.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Joan Lipton papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Related Materials
related
Collection Overview
Collection includes clippings, proof pages, storyboards, writings, speeches and other printed materials that primarily document Lipton's career at McCann Erickson during the 1970s and 1980s. Advertisements relate to a variety of personal consumer products including lotions and other cosmetics, baby care, contraception and family planning. Companies represented include Gillette, Johnson & Johnson, Mennen (now part of Colgate-Palmolive), Ortho, Pepperell, and Tampax. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Advertising executives; Women in the advertising industry; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Johnson & Johnson Baby Products Company; West Point Pepperell (Firm)
- Advertisements with scores, undated (Box 1)
- Advertiser's Weekly (U.K.) clippings, 1965 (Box 1)
- Awards, 1974-1984 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes nomination materials for Ad Woman of the Year.
- Press and publicity, 1975-2001 (Box 1)
- Proofs and storyboards--Johnson & Johnson baby products, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
- Proofs and storyboards--Mennen (Balm Barr), 1981 and undated (Box 1)
- Proofs and storyboards--Miscellaneous, 1963-1984 and undated (Box 1)
  Includes Beech Nut baby cereal, Campbell Soup, Coffee Mixer, Erasermate, Florida Citrus, L'Oreal, Tavern Key, Wall Street Journal
- Proofs and storyboards--Ortho (Conceptrol, Gynol II contraceptives, Fact home pregnancy test), 1976-1982 (Box 1)
- Proofs and storyboards--Pepperell, undated (Box 1)
- Proofs and storyboards--Tampax, undated (Box 1)
- Speech--Advertising Women of Los Angeles: Women Who Work, 1977 (Box 1)
- Speech--Communicating to Women Through Advertising, undated (Box 1)
- Speech--Headline Award acceptance remarks (Women in Communications, Inc.), 1976 (Box 1)
- Speech--Someone to Watch Over Me (Matrix Awards), 1980 (Box 1)
- Writings--Career Overview, undated (Box 1)
- Writing--My Dinner at Rao's, approximately 1998 (Box 1)